ANSAF ABUSALIHU

20A, AMI Naina Marikkar St, Spill Road, Puttalam 61300, Sri Lanka Email: ansafsah@gmail.com | Mobile: +94 77 857 6936 | Skype: ansafsah

Personal Statement

A passionate, senior software engineer professional with more than 7 years of hands-on experience on JavaScript, PHP, Java and Mobile application frameworks, excellent knowledge on keeping atop of new developments within the industry and able to quickly learn and adapt to new technologies.

Skills

Programming: JavaScript (ES5 & ES6), TypeScript, PHP & Java

Stacks: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Angular, React, Node.js, NestJS, Spring Boot, Laravel, Symfony,

Ionic, Eloquent ORM, Doctrine ORM, TypeORM, jQuery, GraphQL, NgRx, Redux,

Bootstrap, PrimeNg, Material UI

Tools: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, Jenkins, Spinnaker, Argo CD, AWS (Amazon

Web Services), GCS (Google Cloud Services), Linux, Bash, Git, JIRA, GitHub, GitLab,

Bitbucket, Trello, Agile Framework (Sprint & Kanban)

Languages: English, Tamil

Professional Experience

Cloud Solutions International Pvt Ltd.

Colombo, Sri Lanka Jul 2022 – Current

Senior Software Engineer

- Mentoring junior developers, performing technical discussions and supports, assigning tasks for junior developers.
- Daily code reviews conducted for pull requests, followed SOLID principles and best practices to maintain code quality and scalability within projects.
- Worked on a major role of converting legacy Angular projects to micro frontend and implementation of micro frontend architecture with the support of Angular module federation library.
- Maintained ReactJs projects, converted UIs into React components and experienced in implementing state management (Redux).
- Implemented, global shared state management between micro frontend applications with NgRx

Software Engineer

Feb 2020 - Jul 2022

- Involved in developing complex features of enterprise applications used by the largest hospitals in middle east regions, also having extensive domain knowledge in the healthcare industry.
- Worked on R&Ds to develop the base layout of Angular projects.
- Used caching and memorizing techniques to optimize Angular applications and custom libraries.
- Preparing and maintaining monthly production release branches in Bitbucket repositories, building Docker images with Jenkins, deployed using Spinnaker or Argo CD tools.
- Experienced working on Agile software development such as Sprint (Daily scrum, grooming,

planning and retrospective) and Kanban frameworks.

Associate Software Engineer

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

- Worked on a major role of converting modules and components to Angular libraries, managed common libraries.
- Libraries managed and published by Sementic versioning best practices in private NPM server.
- Created and managed markdown documentations for Angular libraries.

Imara Software Solutions Pvt Ltd

Sri Lanka

Full Stack Software Developer

Sep 2018 - Jul 2019

- Managed user portal to customize ebay descriptions using Ebay REST APIs which was built in Laravel.
- Developed a JavaScript project using LeafletJs to draw and mark coordinates by imported CSV files.

Freelancing - Remote

United States

Full Stack Software Developer

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

- Designed and developed PHP Laravel project client and admin panel with REST APIs for Parking management system.
- Developed separate Ionic mobile applications for admin and other users.
- Project integrated with the following services: SMS notifications (Nexmo API), Payment gateway (Paypal API), NodeJs Websocket server (Socket.io) for real time chat.
- OpenALPR plugin integration to read vehicle number plates by capturing images.
- Deployment of Laravel projects on AWS (EC2).

Adsfly.lk Internship & Full Stack Software Developer Sri Lanka Aug 2016 – Sep 2018

- Designed and developed PHP MVC MPAs (Multi page applications) using Laravel and MySQL respectively Hotel management, Inventory management, a website for advertisements.
- WordPress plugin developments, modifications for Woo-commerce templates
- Developed Laravel REST APIs for mobile apps with Ionic Framework.
- Manage private hostings and deployments
- Designed and developed a PHP Symfony project and admin panel for foreign money transfer and currency exchange with admin using PHP Symfony framework and MySQL.

Education

University of Colombo, Sri Lanka

Mar 2017 - Jun 2021

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology (BIT)

Links

Portfolio https://ansafans.github.io

GitHub https://github.com/ansafans

LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/ansafans

Stack overflow https://stackoverflow.com/users/8482039/ansaf-ans

More references to be provided upon request.